

Wu Zhou Software Engineer



Profile

I am a software engineer currently developing data related IT products for digital media industry. I enjoy problem solving, particularly those involve logical thinking. With 5-year experience in software industry, my passion for technologies never fades but only grows stronger. I am looking for a job that brings out my potentials and skills to deliver products that can make an impact on people's life.

*Visa status: PR



Contact

+65 85400152 wuzhou831@gmail.com



Skills

Programming

- JavaScript/Angular/jQuery
- ASP.Net/C#
- HTML5/CSS(Bootstrap, Angular Material)
- Database/SQL Server
- Python
- C++/C
- Java

Familiar With

- Agile development (Scrum)
- SDLC & Version control (git, bitbucket)
- MVC Framework
- REST API
- Apache Kylo/Apache Nifi
- Machine learning/Keras/Scikitlearn

Language

- English
- Mandarin Chinese

Work Experience

Senior Data Technology Developer

Dentsu Aegis Network

- Develop front-end features for a cloud based data lake solution powered by the open source project Kylo. Collaborate with teammates to achieve data extraction, management and scheduling by orchestrating front-end and backend systems in a single platform. Work with third party APIs (Google, MediaMath, etc.) to build scalable ETL solutions.
- The sole full stack developer for data analytics web applications that are driven by Angular and asp.Net framework. Design and implement features to provide dynamic, interactive data visualization functions, such as charts and dashboards, within and across data sets.
- Implement, improve and maintain the ETL process for data used by the data analytics applications.
- Provide optimized automation solutions for data visualization results exporting in multiple formats including images, crosstabs, and demo-able slides with editable charts.

Software Engineer

Ascenz Solutions Pte Ltd.

02/2017 - 11/2017

11/2017 - Now

- Individually developed a module that analyzes bunkering processes to detect and classify bunker states which can assist ship owners in identifying and preventing frauds. Deployed the module as a web application and created APIs to work with existing web product. Integrated the module with on-board devices to provide real-time analysis.
- Worked as full stack developer for a web portal using jQuery and .Net. Developed and maintained features like vessel tracking, geo-fence monitoring, data visualization and report generation etc.
- Conducted investigation of issues and provided fixes. Worked closely with sales and marketing to answer to customers' requests.

Software Engineer

07/2013 - 02/2017

Gemalto

- Developed and maintained operation systems for SIM card using C and Java. Successfully optimized OS size by 50% saving manufacturing time. Analyzed security vulnerabilities and implemented security enhancing features.
- Designed validation plans and created small java card testing applets and test scripts with VB.Net against various specifications and real life scenarios. Managed validation everyday reporting.

Lab Teaching Assistant (Part-time) NUS

04/2013 - 08/2010

- Tutored students in an elementary programming course using C.
- Supervised labs, marked tests and provided tutorials on all lab tasks. Reply to students' enquiries actively



Education

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering, First Honour.

2009 - 2013

National University of Singapore



Awards & Certificates

NICF-Object Oriented Analysis & Design (IT-DD-403S-1, IT-DE-402S-1, ID-TE -507S-1).

NICF-Software Testing (IT-TE-302S-1, IT-TE-402S-1).

WSQ Implementing Design Thinking (CI-DES-342C-1).

Innovation & Research Award: Merit Award on Final Year Project